The Helen Wright Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Helen Wright Papers
1906-1954
MSS 2
Yale University Music Library
0.25
(1 box)
The Helen Wright Papers consist primarily of letters from Myra Hess and Teresa Carreño. They also contain photographs, clippings, and miscellaneous items.
Wright, Helen Madeline
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Helen Wright Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Mrs. Arnold Hall, ca. 1961.
Arrangement
In 4 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Miscellaneous items. III. Photographs. IV. Printed matter.
Scope and Contents
The Helen Wright Papers consist primarily of correspondence written to Wright by her piano teachers Myra Hess (1890-1965) and Teresa Carreño (1853-1917). The Papers also contain signed photographs of Hess and Carreño, newspaper clippings, and miscellaneous items.
Pianists -- Correspondence; Carreño, Teresa, 1853-1917; Hess, Myra, Dame, 1890-1965; Tagliapietra, Giovanni, 1846-1921; Wright, Helen Madeline; Davis-Chase, Anita
- Correspondence, 1907-1954; Series I
  - Hess, Myra, 1931-1949; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hess, Myra, 1945-1947; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hess, Myra, 1937-1949; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hess, Myra, 1951-1953; 6 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hess, Myra, 1952 Jan 28; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hess, Myra, 1950-1954; 3 cards (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hess, Myra, 1954; typed schedule of tours in U.S.A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Davis-Chase, Anita, 1946-1953; 4 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Davis-Chase, Anita, 1953 Feb 24; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Wright, Helen to Myra Hess, 1953 May 11; telegram (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carreño, Teresa, 1907-1915; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Tagliapietra, Giovanni, 1946 May 11; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Items, Series II
  - Miscellaneous Items, 15 unidentified items (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photographs, Series III
  - Hess, Myra, 2 signed photographs (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carreño, Teresa, 6 signed photographs, 2 photographs (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Printed Matter, Series IV
  - "Dame Myra Hess", 1945 Jun 14; autographed book (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "National Gallery Concerts", London, 1945; autographed book (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hess, Myra, newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Carreño, Teresa, newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 11)